The story you've never seen.
The Grey Zone is a drama, war, history film directed by Tim Blake Nelson.
The story of Auschwitz's twelfth Sonderkommando — one of the thirteen consecutive "Special Squads" of Jewish prisoners placed by the Nazis in
the excruciating moral dilemma of assisting in the extermination of fellow Jews in exchange for a few more months of life.
Hoffman, played by David Arquette.
Moll, played by Velizar Binev.
Cohen, played by Michael Stuhlbarg.
Simon Schlermer, played by Daniel Benzali.
Nyiszli, played by Allan Corduner.
'Hesch' Abramowics, played by Steve Buscemi.
The Grey Zone is a 2001 American historical tragedy film written and directed by Tim Blake Nelson and
starring David Arquette, Steve Buscemi, Harvey Keitel, Mira Sorvino, and Daniel Benzali.
It is based on the book Auschwitz: A Doctor's Eyewitness Account written by Dr.
Miklós Nyiszli.
The title comes from a chapter in the book The Drowned and
the Saved by Holocaust survivor Primo Levi.
The film tells the story of the Jewish
Sonderkommando XII in Auschwitz in October 1944.
These prisoners were made to assist the camp's guards in shepherding their victims
to the gas chambers and then disposing of their bodies in the ovens.
The film explores themes of nazi, holocaust (shoah),
auschwitz-birkenau concentration camp, uprising, doctor.
The tone is emotional.